The Bailey Collection
The Bailey Collection
- Cheshire Manorial Court Rolls, 1569-1745; GB/418/Bundle 37 no 331-Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16; Chetham's Library
  - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1580-1701; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3; Chetham's Library
    This sub-series of court records refer to the court leet, view of frankpledge and court baron for the barony of Nantwich (Wich Malbank), consisting of the townships of Nantwich, Stoke, Aston and Cholmeston. During the medieval period Nantwich was under the jurisdiction of the Abbey of Combermere, but following its dissolution in July 1538 its possessions were forfeit to the crown, and Sir Thomas Foulehurst, the Steward to the Countess of Warwick's Fee, was made Chief Officer of the town. In 1562 Sir Thomas's son, Robert Foulehurst, sold the Fee of the Countess of Warwick to Sir Christopher Hatton. Thus, Sir Christopher Hatton became Lord of the Manor of Nantwich and the townships of Nantwich, Stoke, Aston and Cholmeston became answerable to him. The ancient parishes of Nantwich and Acton in South Cheshire lay within the barony of Nantwich.
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1580; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/1; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1584; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/2; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1587; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/3; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1588; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/4; 3 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1589; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/5; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1590; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/6; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1592; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/7; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1593; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/8; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1594; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/9; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1595; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/10; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1597; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/11; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1609; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/12; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1610; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/13; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1611; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/14; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1612; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/15; 4 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1613; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/16; 3 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1614; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/17; 3 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1615; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/18; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1616; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/19; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1617; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/20; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1618; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/21; 3 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1619; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/22; 3 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1620; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/23; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1621; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/24; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1622; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/25; 3 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1623; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/26; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1624; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/27; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1625; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/28; 4 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1626; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/29; 3 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1627; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/30; 4 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1628; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/31; 3 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1629; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/32; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1630; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/33; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1632; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/34; 5 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1635; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/35; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1641; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/36; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1642; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/37; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1645; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/38; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1647; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/39; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1649; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/40; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      1 item is a loose sheet of papers
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1650; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/41; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1652; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/42; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1653; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/43; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1654; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/44; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1668; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/45; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1669; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/46; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1686-1689; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/47; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1688; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/48; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1689; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/49; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1690; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/50; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1691; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/51; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1692; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/52; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1693; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/53; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1694; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/54; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1695; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/55; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1697; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/56; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court rolls relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1698; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/57; 2 items; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1699; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/58; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1700; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/59; Chetham's Library
    - Manorial court roll relating to Nantwich, Ches, 1701; GB/418/Bundle 38 no 334; GB/418/Bailey/16/3/60; Chetham's Library
- Protestation of 1641-2: Lists of the Protestors for the whole of Lancashire, GB/418/C.7.25 Bundle 17; GB/418/Bailey/17; 13 bundles; Chetham's Library
  19th century transcripts copied from the originals in the House of Lords Record Office.
  In 1641-2 Parliament ordered all males in England and Wales over the age of 18 to take an oath to "live and die for the true Protestant religion, the liberties and rights of subjects, and the privilege of Parliaments". Churchwardens and constables made lists of all who signed and of those who refused to sign. Bailey's transcripts were copied from the originals in the House of Lords Record Office. Bailey described the Manchester list as "perhaps the earliest and completest list of the inhabitants of Manchester that could be found...They form an excellent basis for the calculation of population, and for the study of Lancashire nomenclature; while they are invaluable for historic and genealogical purposes. All the then well-known names of Lancashire men are found in the lists" (J. E. Bailey,Palatine Note-Book, volume I (1880-84), p 80).
  Returns have been preserved for the hundreds of Amounderness, Blackburn, Leyland, Salford and West Derby.
  The Manchester section of these transcripts was printed by Bailey inThe Palatine Note-Book, volume 1, 1881, pp 80 et seq.
  B. G. Blackwood,The Lancashire Gentry and the Great Rebellion, Chetham Society, 3rd Series vol 25 (1978).
  R. Stewart-Brown, The inhabitants of Liverpool from the 14th to the 18th century (Liverpool, 1930).
  - Protestation of 1641-2., GB/418/C.7.25 Bundle 17; GB/418/Bailey/17/1; Chetham's Library
    19th century transcripts
    (1) West Derby Hundred
    (2) Miscellaneous notes and 2 loose pages not yet identified
    (3) Salford Hundred: Ashton-under-Lyne parish
    (4) Salford Hundred: Bolton and Deane parishes
    (5) Salford Hundred: Rochdale parish
    (6) Salford Hundred: Bury and Radcliffe parishes
    (7) Salford Hundred: Middleton parish
    (8) Salford Hundred: Manchester parish (Manchester as printed in volume 1 of The Palatine Note-Book and manuscript index notes)
    (9) Salford Hundred: Ardwick, Birch, Blackley, Cheetham, Chorlton Row, Crumpsall, Denton, Didsbury, Withington, Burnage, Levenshulme, Eccles, Flixton, Gorton, Harpurhey, Haughton, Heaton Norris, Newton Heath, Openshaw, Prestwich, Oldham, Reddish, Salford, Stretford
    (10) Salford Hundred: Manchester parish. Proof of printed version (The Palatine Note-Book 1) of Manchester
    (11) Leyland Hundred
    (12) Blackburn Hundred
    (13) Amounderness Hundred